77. Rock Climbing It gives me a chance to feel like a kid again,
says Sherry. I love the challenge. I love the outdoors. I love that it is a very individual
sport, says Mark. I believe the mountains were made for me to climb them, says Colin.
They're all talking about rock climbing or mountain climbing, a sport that is both exciting
and sometimes deadly. Rock climbing is what it sounds like, crawling up a rock, using
your hands and feet. Climbers ascend nearly vertical rock faces, sometimes hundreds of
feet in the air. They climb little by little, sometimes only moving inches at a time. Because
they climb so high above hard rock surfaces, climbing can be very dangerous. For this reason,
many climbers use safety equipment. They may wear special climbing shoes or gloves
that help them grip rocks. They often use ropes to stop them if they fall. Some wear
helmets to protect their heads from falling rocks. The danger of climbing both pulls people
to the sport and pushes them away. The danger adds to the thrill of the sport. Statistically,
climbing is much safer than driving in a car. People playing football and soccer hurt
themselves more often, but the danger of climbing is real. Alone, halfway up a mountain, there's
no one to save you but yourself. Climbing forces you to take care of yourself, but accidents
happen. Rocks break, climbing partners slip, and people trip over the ropes. One small
mistake can mean death. Rock climbing is an intense, individual challenge for your
mind and body. If you want to try rock climbing, practice in a climbing gym first. Gain strength,
experience, and confidence. Then, see if you're one of those people who want to tackle mountains.